Guide to the Ski Utah audio-visual collection undated
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Ski Utah audio-visual collection
undated
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0590
Ski Utah, Inc.
20 16mm films, 22 VHS videocassettes, 10 U-matic videocassettes, 3 Betacam videocassettes, 4 compact discs
The Ski Utah audio-visual collection consists largely of promotional films, videos and compact discs designed to attract tourists to Utah on behalf of the ski and snowboard industry. The collection also includes a some news stories related to Utah's ski industry. Ski Utah, Inc. is a marketing firm represnting the state's resorts and related service industries.
Organizational History
Ski Utah, Inc. was founded in 1978 as the marketing firm for the Utah Ski and Snowboard Association, a non-profit trade organization founded in 1975, with the aim of promoting Utah's ski and snowboard industry. The organizations represent the state's resorts, lodging, transportation, retail, restaurants and other ski or snowboard related services. Ski Utah works to create brand awareness for Utah's winter sports industry.
The Ski Utah audio-visual collection consists largely of promotional films, videos and compact discs designed to attract tourists to Utah on behalf of the ski and snowboard industry. The collection also includes a some news stories related to Utah's ski industry.
The materials are arranged by format type. 16mm films are followed by videocassettes and compact discs.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
See also the Ski Utah photograph collection (P0913).
Skiing--Utah--History; Snowboarding; Tourism; Advertising and Marketing; Sports and Recreation; Moving Images; Sound Recordings; Moving images; Sound recordings
- 16mm films
  - Utah! The greatest snow on Earth, 16mm film Optical soundtrack, color (Reel 1)
    The film begins with shots of mountainsides, the sun rising and setting and snow falling on pine trees. After the title sequence, we see shots of skiers on the slopes. These are the characters that will dominate much of the film and they are identified as members of the local Ski Patrol. There is also footage of skiers paying for lift tickets, children competing in Junior Ski competitions, hot air balloons, youth ski school classes and dog-sled competitions.
    The film then shifts to show the nightlife of the resorts. We see shots of people barbequing, eating in lodges and restaurants and waving at the camera. The next images are of the Salt Lake International Airport. The camera follows one particular skier with a Snowbird resort jacket on as he arrives in Salt Lake and takes a Taxi to his hotel. There are a few images of buildings in Salt Lake as well as a shot of the city skyline during daylight hours. In addition, we are given a glimpse of the entertainment that the city has to offer visitors. There is footage of people watching a basketball game (unidentified teams) as well as a Hockey game featuring the Salt Lake Golden Eagles). There is also a short montage of various alcoholic beverages available in the city as well as a short bit of footage of a ballet performance and a woman playing the violin in an orchestra. The film then shifts back to the skiers (members of Ski Patrol) and the nightlife afforded them. We see footage of an after dark drum circle followed by that of a country and western band. There are shots of people warming themselves in front of a fire and cooking meat on an outdoor grill. Finally, we see footage of a helicopter with the members of the Ski Patrol inside it take off for a mountain top not used by ordinary skiers. The helicopter lands and the skiers file out and proceed down the slope. After a montage highlighting their skiing prowess the film ends.
    Utah Ski Resorts and Areas Seen in Film:
    Alta, Beaver Mountain, Brian Head, Brighton, Deer Valley, Mt. Holly, Nordic Valley, Park City, Park West, Parley's Summit, Powder Mountain, Snow Basin, Snowbird, Solitude, Sundance.
    Produced by the Utah Travel Council by Telescene, Inc. Salt lake City, Utah.
    Director: Art Wilder
    Cameramen: Bruce Aoki, Art Wilder
    Production Coordinator: Virginia Timmons
    Editor: Art Wilder
    Narrator: Richard Ramos
    Musical Score: Larry Bastian
  - Authorized personnel only, 16mm film Black and white (Reel 2)
  - Utah! The greatest snow on Earth, 16mm film Color (Reel 3-4)
    Short version
  - Utah! The greatest snow on Earth, 16mm film Color (Reel 5-6)
    Incomplete short version
  - A matter of decision, 16mm film Black and white (Reel 7)
  - Utah! The greatest snow on Earth, 16mm film Color (Reel 8)
  - Freestyle with Jean Claude Killy, 16mm film Color (Reel 9)
  - Utah! The greatest snow on Earth, 16mm film Color (Reel 10)
    Long version
  - Buddy Werner races, 16mm film Black and white (Reel 11)
  - Professional Freestyle Association, 16mm film Color (Reel 12)
  - Ski Park City, 16mm film Color (Reel 13)
  - Skiing is believing, 16mm film Color (Reel 14)
  - Professionals, 16mm film Color (Reel 15)
  - Helix, 16mm film Color (Reel 16)
    United States version
  - Authorized personnel only, 16mm film Color (Reel 17)
  - A matter of decision, 16mm film Color (Reel 18)
  - Skiing film of Matumoto Ski Club, 16mm film Color (Reel 19)
  - Utah! The greatest snow on Earth, 16mm film Color (Reel 20)
- Videocasettes
  - Ski Utah media day, 1984 December 11; VHS videocassette (Cassette 1)
    KUTV News, Prime Time Access/Other
  - Ski Utah miscellaneous footage, VHS videocassette (Cassette 2-3)
  - Ski Utah, 1991 December 31; VHS videocassette (Cassette 4)
    Rocky Mountain Motion Pictures
  - Ski Utah, VHS videocassette (Cassette 5)
    Various shots cleared for broadcast
  - Ski Salt Lake, 1995; VHS videocassette (Cassette 6)
  - Snowbird - skiing above all else, VHS videocassette (Cassette 7)
  - Beaver Mountain promotional, 1995; VHS videocassette (Cassette 8)
  - All that glitters is not gold, VHS videocassette (Cassette 9)
  - Winter vacation planner, 1992 November 20; VHS videocassette (Cassette 10)
  - Ski Utah promotional, VHS videocassette (Cassette 11)
  - Ski Utah, VHS videocassette (Cassette 12)
  - Ski Brian Head, VHS videocassette (Cassette 13)
  - Skinners Ogden Valley, 1989 November 22; VHS videocassette (Cassette 14)
  - Mike Allen stories, VHS videocassette (Cassette 15)
  - Utah news clips, VHS videocassette (Cassette 16)
  - Back roads prototype, VHS videocassette (Cassette 17)
    PM Magazine Utah (KUTV)
  - The quest ...... staying on top, VHS videocassette (Cassette 18)
  - Utah Winter Games news clip, 1987; VHS videocassette (Cassette 19)
  - Youth Ski League - Small World Cup, VHS videocassette (Cassette 20)
    Rocky Division copy
  - Ski Utah, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 21)
  - Snowbird travelview, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 22)
  - Ski it to believe it, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 23)
  - Deer Valley video press release, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 24)
  - Ski riders, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 25)
  - Ski Utah miscellaneous footage, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 26)
  - Ski Utah Inc., VHS videocassette (Cassette 27)
  - Hot shots unlimited, VHS videocassette (Cassette 28)
  - Snowbird miscellaneous winter video, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 29)
  - Ski riders of the Wasatch, 1987; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 30)
  - Ski Utah promotional video, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 31)
  - Ski Utah interconnect, 1984 January 29-March 14; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 32)
    KUTV, PM Magazine
  - Ski Utah promotional, Betacam videocassette (Cassette 33)
  - Unidentified video, Betacam videocassette (Cassette 34)
  - Olympic announcement, Betacam videocassette (Cassette 35)
- Compact discs
  - Wickline: A world of white, Compact disc (Disc 36-37)
    Ski music album
  - Discovering Utah, CD-ROM (Disc 38-39)
    Multimedia "Ski-D-Rom" guide